The Overnighters is a drama, documentary film directed by Jesse Moss.
Desperate, broken men chase their dreams and run from
their demons in the North Dakota oil fields.
A local Pastor's decision to help them has
extraordinary and unexpected consequences.
Himself, played by Keegan Edwards.
Himself, played by Jay Reinke.
The Overnighters is a 2014 American documentary film
written, directed, and produced by Jesse Moss.
It premiered on January 18, 2014, as part of the U.S.
Documentary Competition section of the Sundance Film Festival,
and it won the festival's Special Jury Prize.
The film also won a prize at the Miami International Film
Festival, at which it was screened on March 13, 2014.
After its premiere at Sundance, Drafthouse Films
acquired the film's distribution rights.
It was released on October 24, 2014, in United States, with a portion of all box office
receipts being donated to affordable housing charities in North Dakota.
The film explores themes of north dakota, human
rights, oil industry, found footage.
The tone is emotional.